Guide to the Dana Plante (Class of 1959) Collection, 1954 - 1960
Dana Plante (Class of 1959) Collection, 1954 - 1960
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Plante, Dana.
2005-19
0.75
2
Dana Plante (1937-1960) graduated in 1959 from Wesleyan University.
The Dana Plante Collection contains memorabilia from Plante's high school and college years.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Gift of Sarah M. Plante, March 2005.
Biographical Note
Dana G. Plante was born in Fall River, Massachusetts on March 18, 1937 and graduated from Case High School in Swansea, Massachusetts in 1955. Following his graduation from Wesleyan in 1959, Plante worked for Travelers Insurance Company in Hartford, Conn. He was inducted into the army on November 15, 1959, and died of a viral attack while training at Fort Dix in New Jersey. Plante was survived by his mother, Sarah M. Plante, and his twin brother, Dale S. Plante.
Collection Overview
This collection contains various memorabilia from both the high school and college careers of Dana Plante, Wesleyan University Class of 1959. Plante was highly honored and well-liked and respected by his classmates and professors. He also distinguished himself academically. Items in the collection are almost exclusively academic in nature and include several award medals that Plante received in various fields.
In addition to the high school and college memorabilia, the collection also includes notes from the donor and Plante's obituary in the Wesleyan University Alumnus in February 1960.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Plante, Dana G.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni and alumnae.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - Letters/envelopes received from Mrs. Sarah M. Plante with donation (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Obituary from Wesleyan University Alumnus, February 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Joseph Case High School diploma, 1955 (Folder 3)
  - Congratulations card for high school graduation, 1955 (Folder 4)
  - The Harvard Prize Book, presented June 17, 1954 by the Harvard Club of Fall River, Massachusetts (Folder 5)
  - Photograph of Plante receiving The Harvard Prize Book, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - The Chief Yearbook for Joseph Case High School, class of 1955 (Folder 7)
  - National Honor Society membership card, undated (Folder 8)
  - Bausch & Lomb Honorary Science Award medal and pamphlet, 1955 (Folder 9)
  - Rensselaer medal and pamphlet, undated (Folder 10)
  - Charles Palmer-Davis award medal, undated (Folder 11)
  - Wesleyan University diploma, class of 1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Grade Report for final semester, spring 1959 (Folder 2)
  - Congratulations card from mother upon college graduation, 1959 (Folder 3)
  - Wesleyan University's 127th Commencement program, class of 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Brownstone and Brick, senior thesis, Stuart D. Anderson, co-author, 1959 (Folder 5)